anglia.ac.uk 2017-06-06

# Privacy and cookies - Anglia Ruskin University

Untitled Page

### Privacy policy

Anglia Ruskin University is committed to protecting your privacy online. Please read the following privacy policy to understand how we use and protect the information obtained from those visiting and using the Anglia Ruskin University website www.anglia.ac.uk (the 'Site').

The Site is operated by Anglia Ruskin University. Anglia Ruskin University and its partner institutions will use the information we collect from you in accordance with this policy. A list of our associated partners can be found at www.anglia.ac.uk/about-us/global-partnerships.

If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to our processing please contact [dpa@anglia.ac.uk](mailto:dpa@anglia.ac.uk).

By using the Site you consent to the collection/retention and use of your personal information in accordance with this policy.

#### What information do we collect?

  * We collect email addresses.
  * Online applications: if you make an online application to a course we will ask for your name, email address, geographical address and other personal information.
  * From time to time we will ask you for further information, for example if you make a purchase or enter a competition.
  * We may also use cookies. For an explanation, see the section on cookies below.
  * We may also obtain information from you if you use our QR (Quick Response) codes. For an explanation, see the section on QR codes below.

#### How do we use your information?

We use your information:

  * To enable us to supply you with the services and information which you have requested;
  * To ensure that content from the Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * To analyse the information we collect so that we can administer, support and improve and develop the Site;
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may contact you by post, telephone or fax as well as by email, SMS and MMS. If you change your mind about being contacted in the future by any of these means then please contact [dpa@anglia.ac.uk](mailto:dpa@anglia.ac.uk).

#### How do we share information?

Anglia Ruskin University and its partners collect and store the addresses and email addresses of customers who study with us or who enquire direct to us.

Data is used for a range of university activities, including the mailing of university magazines and other university publications, the promotion of benefits and services provided by the university, notification of university events. We may also contact you on occasion about new courses we think might be of interest to you. Under the terms of the Data Protection Act you have the right to object to the use of your data for any of the above purposes. If you do wish your name to be removed from our mailing lists please contact [answers@anglia.ac.uk](mailto:answers@anglia.ac.uk) letting us know what you received.

#### How we store your information

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password that enables you to access certain parts of the Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. You must not share passwords with anyone.

Although we maintain a number of safeguards, fraudulent email requests are occasionally delivered to staff and students. We will **never** ask for your username or password by email. Any message that does so should be treated as a potential breach of security, no matter how legitimate it may appear. 

If you are in any doubt, **do nothing** until you have spoken to a member of the IT Services Customer Support Team.

Unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. 

All payment details which are entered through this payment gateway are encrypted when the student, or third party making payment, enters them. The site is secure using 128 bit encryption to offer secure communications by encrypting all data to and from the site.

#### International enquiries

The data sent in international enquiries to the University will be used for the purposes of dealing with your enquiry, and sending you relevant information about Anglia Ruskin University. If you wish to remove yourself from Anglia Ruskin University's database please contact [international@anglia.ac.uk](mailto:international@anglia.ac.uk).

#### Disclosure of your information

Authorised personnel within Anglia Ruskin University and its partners will be able to access the information you provide to us. We may also disclose your information to other third parties who act for us for the purposes set out in the policy or for purposes approved by you.

Please note that where you nominate a third party or an agent to discuss your application/course with us or to make decisions on your behalf and you provide contact details for that third party/agent, you are consenting for us to disclose information relating to your application/course to that third party/agent. 

Please note that countries outside the European Economic Area do not always have the same strong data protection laws. However, we will always take steps to ensure that your information is used by third parties in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

Unless required or permitted to do so by law, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any of the information you provide to us without your consent.

#### Higher Education Statistics Agency (HESA)

Please note that some information that is held about you will be sent to the Higher Education Statistics Agency (HESA). For further information on how this information will be used please [visit the HESA website](https://www.hesa.ac.uk/about/regulation/data-protection/notices).

#### Other websites

The Site may contain links to other web sites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files stored on your device (desktop, tablet, mobile phone etc.) by your device's web browser. They relate to a specific site and can be used to enhance that site's functionality and your interaction with it; they may also be used for usage tracking, research, targeting etc.

Anglia Ruskin uses cookies for a number of purposes including (but not limited to):

  * the logging on process for registered users
  * to help ensure the security and authenticity of registered users
  * to monitor how our Site is used, to plan improvements to user experience, and
  * to enhance the functionality of the Site.

#### Modifying cookie settings

You can also control the use of cookies on your device by adjusting your web browser preferences, choosing to allow them, block them, only allow them from a specific site or only allow certain types of cookies.

Further information about how to manage cookies on some of the most commonly used web browsers can be found below:

  * [Apple Safari (desktop)](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH19214?locale=en_US&viewlocale=en_GB) / [Safari (mobile)](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265)
  * [Google Chrome (desktop)](https://support.google.com/chrome/?hl=en-GB#topic=3227046) / [Chrome (mobile)](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/2392971?hl=en-GB)

To edit settings for Local Shared Objects, also known as 'flash cookies', used by some Adobe Flash Player applications, guidance can be found on the [Flash Player Help](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player.html).

#### QR (Quick Response) Codes

Anglia Ruskin occasionally uses QR codes for marketing purposes. Enquirers are able to scan QR codes using their mobile phone to quickly retrieve further information.

Please note that Anglia Ruskin will track individuals, who scan QR codes and this will mean obtaining some personal data about them. Information obtained will include the device, the type of phone, how many pages they visit and the phone network that they are using.

Please note that by scanning QR codes enquirers give consent to Anglia Ruskin University to process all personal data contained within the codes.

#### Access rights

You have the right to access the personal data that is held about you in our records and you may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that it is accurate and kept up to date. If you would like to do this, you should contact [dpa@anglia.ac.uk](mailto:dpa@anglia.ac.uk). We are entitled by law to charge a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information that we hold about you.

#### Intellectual Property Rights

The information, images and documents on the Anglia Ruskin website are copyright of Anglia Ruskin University unless otherwise stated. It is forbidden to reproduce any information without prior consent from Anglia Ruskin University.

#### Web statistics

We monitor website traffic to assist in the continuous improvement and development of the site, but do this only by monitoring IP addresses that are not linked in any way to any personal data, retaining the anonymity of our visitors.

#### Image Capture

Anglia Ruskin University produces a range of published materials and online information. We often take photographic/video images of subjects in order to enhance and illustrate our materials and make them more motivating and inspiring to our audiences.

For children under 16 years of age, full parental/guardian consent is required and Anglia Ruskin University has an Image Consent Form which should be completed. This is available from the University Records Manager, Jackie Barlow at [jackie.barlow@anglia.ac.uk](mailto:jackie.barlow@anglia.ac.uk). For children between 12 and 16 years of age, who have a sufficient understanding of the consent process and its implications for them, the child should be involved in completing the form and their consent should be sought. The child may also sign the form.

As it is mandatory for Anglia Ruskin University to obtain permission prior to each photographic/video session, it is necessary for each child to have a copy of this form signed by the parent/guardian prior to the relevant photographic/video session.

Anglia Ruskin University acknowledges its responsibilities in capturing images by photography or other means under the provisions of the following legislation;

**The Children and Young Persons Act 1963:** Anglia Ruskin University undertakes to seek a licence where necessary from the appropriate local authority for any performance activity in which children are taking part and which may be recorded with a view to being broadcast, published or shown to the public.

**The Protection of Children Act 1978:** Anglia Ruskin University recognises that it is a criminal offence to take, permit to be taken, distribute, have in one's possession or publish indecent photographs (including films and other imagery) of children.

**The Human Rights Act 1998:** Anglia Ruskin University recognises an individual's rights to privacy as protected by this Act.

**The Data Protection Act 1998:** Anglia Ruskin University undertakes to inform all those whose images may be recorded (or their parents/guardians if under 18 years of age) of the purposes for which the images may be used by Anglia Ruskin University.

In this context Anglia Ruskin University informs all persons taking part in university activities that they may be photographed, filmed, videoed or otherwise captured in image form. Where possible and practical to do so, Anglia Ruskin University seeks written consent to image capture. Where this is not possible for practical reasons, unless express objections are received, individuals attending an event at Anglia Ruskin University are deemed to have given their consent by attending or remaining at the event. Any queries or complaints should be raised with the event host in the first instance.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Anglia Ruskin University may from time to time change this Privacy Policy or change, modify or withdraw access to this Site at any time with or without notice. However if this Privacy Policy is changed in a material, adverse way, Anglia Ruskin University will post a notice advising of such change at the beginning of this policy. We recommend that you revisit this Privacy Policy from time to time to learn of any such changes to this Privacy Policy. 

Untitled Page

 **We use cookies on the ARU website to improve your browsing experience, monitor how our site is used, and to aid us with advertising our services.** By continuing to use our site, you're agreeing to us placing cookies outlined in our privacy policy on your device.
